Marcos Afonso Salomão Jr

Senior Developer

São Paulo, SP

marcos_salomao@hotmail.com - +5511982684658

Highly versatile full-stack developer professional, with a very strong background such as designing enterprise solutions and leading development team.

ABOUT ME

I'm software developer with over 10 years of experience, mostly time worked with Java web-based applications and Batches processing.

I'm always seeking challenging roles where I can utilize my skills to assist meeting the organization goals and learn it too in the process.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Banco Votorantim SA - São Paulo, SP - February 2010 to January 2016

Worked on various projects Java web-based applications and batches processing focused in billing to Banking Sector. Main projects:

- Integrated CyberFinancial (vendor system) with Legacy Systems;
- Customized and Deployed CyberFinancial (vendor system);
- Assets recovery application;

Worked with project management methodologies:

- Agile
- PMBoK-based

Responsibilities:

- Led development team;
- Designed and developed software applications;
- Developed tests cases;
- Maintenance (support, enhancements and bug fixes) to production environment;
- Developed business use-case model and UML diagrams;
- Reverse engineered legacy systems;
- Profiling the applications;
- Providing estimates and updates in the project plan;

Environment:

- Linux, Windows
- Java EE
- EJB, WebService
- Spring
- JBOSS, Apache Tomcat. HTTP Apache

- ORACLE, Sybase
- JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
- Jenkins, Maven, JUnit
- Automac (UC4)

Scrum Master, Senior Java Developer

RGM - São Paulo, SP - May 2005 to January 2011

Responsibilities

- Led development team;
- Designed and drafted solution architecture;
- Provided systems integrations;
- Designed class and sequence diagrams;
- Maintained applications servers;
- Maintained continuous integration server (Cruise Control);
- Coaching;

Accomplishments

Worked on ERP for Government built in Java EE web-based technology, designed to manager budget planning and financial flow, might as well accountability and reports modules.

Skills Used

- Windows
- Java EE
- EJB, JMS and Hibernate
- JBOSS, Apache Tomcat. HTTP Apache
- ORACLE, Sybase, SQL Server
- Struts, JSP, Taglibs
- CruiseControl, ANT, JUnit
- Jasper Reports
- Scrum

Worked with project management methodologies:

- Agile;
- CMMi-based;

Senior Software Analyst

IBM - São Paulo, SP - December 2003 to April 2005

Responsibilities

- Led development team;
- Designed and developed software applications;
- Developed tests cases;
- Maintenance (support, enhancements and bug fixes) to production environment;
- Developed business use-case model and UML diagrams;
- Reverse engineered legacy systems;
- Profiling the applications;
- Providing estimates and updates in the project plan;

Accomplishments

Worked on various projects Java web-based applications and batches processing focused in billing to Banking Sector. Main projects:

- Integrated CyberFinancial (vendor system) with Legacy Systems;
- Customized and Deployed CyberFinancial (vendor system);
- Assets recovery application;

Skills Used

- Linux, Windows
- Java EE
- EJB, WebService
- Spring
- JBOSS, Apache Tomcat. HTTP Apache
- ORACLE, Sybase
- JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
- Jenkins, Maven, JUnit
- Automac (UC4)

IT Internship

Sybase - São Paulo, SP - 2001 to 2003

Responsibilities

- Maintenance Windows NT/2000, UNIX and Lotus Notus servers, might as weel network windows NT;
- Supported hardware, software and all company users issues;
- Assembly PC and training rooms;

EDUCATION

Specialization in Project Management

IBTA - São Paulo, SP 2009 to 2010

Bacharel in Computer Science

Universidade do Grande ABC - Santo André, SP 1999 to 2003

SKILLS

Java, Python, Oracle, Uml, Web Development, Software Development, Scrum

LINKS

https://github.com/salomax

CERTIFICATIONS

SCJP

SCJA

ITIL

Scrum Master